Guide to the Helen and Kurt Wolff Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Harcourt Brace Jovanovich Papers, 1888-1993; Series IV; 6.05' (15 boxes)
  - WRITINGS
    - Odojewski, Wlodzimierz
      - Island of Salvation
        - Book jacket material, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1801)
        - Book jacket, [1965] (Box 63, Folder 1802)
    - Origo, Iris
      - Images and Shadows: Part of a Life
        - Photographs, 1888-1930, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1803-1805)
          Includes photographs of Antonio and Iris Origo, Lord and Lady Desart, Gaetano Salvemini, Ignazio Silone, de Bosis, Draper, and others
      - A Need to Testify
        - Publicity, [1984?] (Box 63, Folder 1806)
        - Book jacket blurb, [1984?] (Box 63, Folder 1807)
        - Reviews, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 1808)
      - The World of San Bernardino
        - Table of Contents, 1961 Mar 13 (Box 63, Folder 1809)
    - Oz, Amos
      - Black Box
        - Publicity, 1988 Apr 1 (Box 63, Folder 1810)
        - Reviews, 1988-89 (Box 63, Folder 1811)
      - Elsewhere Perhaps
        - Reviews, 1986, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1812)
      - The Hill of Evil Counsel
        - Reviews, 1978 May 28 (Box 63, Folder 1813)
      - In the Land of Israel
        - Publicity, 1983-84 (Box 63, Folder 1814)
          Includes photograph of Oz by Herbert Mitgang
        - Reviews, 1983-84 (Box 63, Folder 1815-1816)
      - A Perfect Peace
        - Publicity, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 1817)
        - Reviews, 1985 Jun (Box 63, Folder 1818)
      - To Know a Woman
        - Synopsis, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1819)
        - Reviews, 1989-91, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1820)
      - Touch the Water, Touch the Wind
        - Reviews, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 1821)
      - Unto Death
        - Reviews, 1975-76 (Box 63, Folder 1822)
    - Pasternak, Aleksandr Leonidovich
      - A Vanished Present
        - Publicity, 1985 Feb 15 (Box 63, Folder 1823)
        - Reviews and brief mentions, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 1824)
    - Pasternak, Boris Leonidovich
      - The Correspondence of Boris Pasternak and Olga Freidenberg, 1910-1954
        - Publicity, 1982 Mar 26 (Box 63, Folder 1825)
        - Reviews, 1982 (Box 63, Folder 1826)
    - Plyushch, Leonid
      - History's Carnival: A Dissident's Autobiography
        - Draft ("Marxist Metanois"), [chapter?], typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1827)
    - Pouillon, Fernand
      - The Stones of the Abbey
        - Publicity, 1985 Jun 2 (Box 63, Folder 1828)
    - Pritchett, V. S. (Victor Sawdon)
      - [ London Perceived ?]
        - Book jacket blurb, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1829)
    - Rawicz, Piotr
      - Blood From the Sky
        - Reader reports, 1961, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1830)
        - Book jacket blurbs, [1963] (Box 63, Folder 1831)
        - Book jacket, 1963 (Box 63, Folder 1832)
    - Reich, Tova
      - Master of the Return
        - Reviews, 1988 (Box 63, Folder 1833)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria
      - Letters, Summer 1926
        - Publicity, 1985 May 31 (Box 63, Folder 1834)
        - Reviews, 1986, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1835)
    - Rio, Michel
      - Parrot's Perch
        - Reader report by Helen Wolff, 1983 Nov 14 (Box 63, Folder 1836)
        - Reviews, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 1837)
    - Robert, Marthe
      - As Lonely as Franz Kafka
        - Reviews, 1982 (Box 63, Folder 1838)
    - Saint-Éxupery, Antoine de
      - Wartime Writings, 1939-1944
        First published as Écrits de Guerre (Paris: Gallimard, 1982)
        - Printed version (French ed.), corrected, 1982 (Box 63, Folder 1839)
        - Drafts of introduction by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, typescript photocopy, corrected (Box 64, Folder 1840)
        - Publicity, 1986 Jun 6 (Box 64, Folder 1841)
        - Reviews and brief mentions, 1986 (Box 64, Folder 1842)
    - [Schmidt, Arno]
      - Republica Intelligentsia
        - Draft, printout, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1843-1844)
    - Semprun, Jorge
      - What a Beautiful Sunday!
        - Reviews, 1982 (Box 64, Folder 1845)
    - Simenon, Georges
      - An American Omnibus
        - Publicity, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 1846)
      - The Bells of Bicetre
        - Publicity, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1847)
      - Intimate Memoirs
        - Reader report [by Helen Wolff?], 1981 Dec 7 (Box 64, Folder 1848)
        - Publicity, 1984 Apr 27 (Box 64, Folder 1849)
        - Reviews, 1982-85, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1850)
        - List of "Questions", n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1851)
        - Draft and galley proof for title page, 1983 (Box 64, Folder 1852)
      - Maigret and the Fortune-Teller
        - Publicity, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 1853)
      - Maigret Bides His Time
        - Reviews and brief mentions, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 1854)
      - Maigret on the Defensive
        - Publicity, [1981] (Box 64, Folder 1855)
      - Maigret on the Riviera
        - Book jacket, [1988?] (Box 64, Folder 1856)
      - Maigret's Memoirs
        - Reviews, 1985-86 (Box 64, Folder 1857)
      - Maigret's Revolver
        - Publicity, [1984?] (Box 64, Folder 1858)
        - Reviews, 1985 Jan 2 (Box 64, Folder 1859)
      - Maigret's War of Nerves
        - Publicity, 1986 Jan 24 (Box 64, Folder 1860)
        - Reviews, 1986 Apr 14 (Box 64, Folder 1861)
      - The Murder
        - Publicity, 1986 Aug 22 (Box 64, Folder 1862)
      - The Rules of the Game
        - Publicity, 1988 Sep 23 (Box 64, Folder 1863)
      - A Simenon Omnibus
        - Book jacket, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1864)
        - List of titles, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1865)
      - The Survivors
        - Reviews and brief mentions, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 1866)
      - The Truth about Bébé Donge
        - Publicity, 1992 Apr 13 (Box 64, Folder 1867)
      - When I was Old
        - Lists of photographs and captions, 1971 Jun (Box 64, Folder 1868)
    - Steinmann, Jean
      - Pascal
        - Reader reports, 1965 (Box 64, Folder 1869)
    - Stirling, Monica
      - The Wild Swan: The Life and Times of Hans Christian Andersen
        - Reader report by Helen Wolff, 1964 Nov 30 (Box 64, Folder 1870)
    - Thorwald, Jürgen
      - Im Zerbrechlichen Haus der Seele
        - Printed version, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1871)
    - Wagner, Cosima
      - Cosima Wagner's Diaries
        - Reviews, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1872)
    - Weiss, Peter
      - The Leavetaking
        First published as Abschied von den Eltern (Frankfurt am Main: Suhrkamp, 1961)
        - Reader report, 1961 May 25 (Box 64, Folder 1873)
    - Zolla, Elémire
      - The Persistence of Unifying Patterns
        - Reviews, 1982 May 16
      - The Writer and the Shaman: A Morphology of the American Indian
        First published as Letterati e lo Sciamano (Milano: Bompiani, 1969)
        - Reader report, 1970 (Box 64, Folder 1874)
    - Unidentified
      - [Empty folder] (Box 64, Folder 1875)
      - "Tale from Island Street," draft (pages 31-51), printout (Box 64, Folder 1876)
  - FINANCIAL AND LEGAL PAPERS
    - Contracts
      - Albin Michel (Firm), 1985 Apr 22 (Box 65, Folder 1877)
      - Chr. Belser AG für Verlagsgeschäfte & Co. KG, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 1878)
      - Cudahy, Sheila, 1982-83 (Box 65, Folder 1879)
      - Ehrlich, Leonard H; Ehrlich, Edith, 1984 Nov 26 (Box 65, Folder 1880)
      - Ermarth, Michael, 1984 (Box 65, Folder 1881)
      - Gallimard (Firm), 1983 Aug 9 (Box 65, Folder 1882)
      - Hermann Luchterhand Verlag, 1980-85 (Box 65, Folder 1883)
      - Inter Nationes, 1986-92 (Box 65, Folder 1884)
      - Jasper, Karl, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1885)
      - Jonathan Cape Limited, 1962 Apr 20 (Box 65, Folder 1886)
      - Johnson, Uwe, 1967 Jun 19 (Box 65, Folder 1887)
      - Julliard (Firm), 1981 Oct 23 (Box 65, Folder 1888)
      - Origo, Iris, 1969 Oct 23 (Box 65, Folder 1889)
      - Pasternak, Eugene, 1978 Feb 27 (Box 65, Folder 1890)
      - Saner, Hans, 1983 Dec 22 (Box 65, Folder 1891)
      - Sasaki, Ruth Fuller, 1965 Feb 10 (Box 65, Folder 1892)
      - Simenon, Georges, 1963-86 (Box 65, Folder 1893)
      - Wolff, Helen; Wolff, Kurt, 1961-83 (Box 65, Folder 1894)
    - Royalty Statements
      - June 30, 1981, 1981 Oct 23 (Box 65, Folder 1895)
      - December 31, 1981, 1982 Apr 23 (Box 65, Folder 1896)
      - June 30, 1982, 1982 Oct 25 (Box 65, Folder 1897)
      - December 31, 1982, 1983 Apr 25 (Box 65, Folder 1898)
      - June 30, 1983, 1983 Oct 25 (Box 65, Folder 1899)
      - December 31, 1983, 1984 Apr 25 (Box 65, Folder 1900)
      - June 30, 1984, 1984 Oct 25 (Box 65, Folder 1901)
      - December 31, 1984, 1985 Apr 25 (Box 65, Folder 1902)
      - June 30, 1985, 1985 Oct 25 (Box 65, Folder 1903)
      - December 31, 1985, 1986 Apr 25 (Box 65, Folder 1904)
      - June 30, 1986, 1986 Oct 24 (Box 65, Folder 1905)
      - December 31, 1986, 1987 Mar 16 (Box 66, Folder 1906)
      - June 30, 1987, 1987 Oct 23 (Box 66, Folder 1907)
      - December 31, 1987, 1988 Mar 15 (Box 66, Folder 1908)
      - June 30, 1988, 1988 Oct 25 (Box 66, Folder 1909)
      - December 31, 1988, 1989 Mar 15 (Box 66, Folder 1910)
      - June 30, 1989, 1989 Oct 25 (Box 66, Folder 1911)
      - December 31, 1989, 1990 Mar 15 (Box 66, Folder 1912)
      - June 30, 1990, 1990 Oct 25 (Box 66, Folder 1913)
      - December 31, 1990, 1991 Mar 15 (Box 66, Folder 1914)
      - June 30, 1991, 1991 Oct 25 (Box 66, Folder 1915)
      - December 31, 1991, 1992 Apr 24 (Box 66, Folder 1916)
      - June 30, 1992 (Box 66, Folder 1917)
      - December 31, 1992, 1993 Apr 23 (Box 66, Folder 1918)
      - June 30, 1993, 1993 Oct 25 (Box 66, Folder 1919)
    - Other Records
      - Annual Report 1967, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 1920)
      - British Rights Sheet, 1982-89 (Box 66, Folder 1921)
      - Certificate for Registration of a Claim to Copyright, 1962-75 (Box 66, Folder 1922)
      - Checks, 1978 Mar 31 (Box 66, Folder 1923)
      - Common Stock Statement, 1993 Nov 23 (Box 66, Folder 1924)
      - Contract Request Form, [1984?] Jan 18 (Box 66, Folder 1925)
      - Contract Signed Memo Amendment, 1981-92 (Box 66, Folder 1926)
      - Correspondence, 1968-93 (Box 66, Folder 1927)
      - Credit Card Charge Form, 1974, 1976 (Box 66, Folder 1928)
      - Dividends and Distribution Tax Form, 1987, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 1929)
      - Domestic Rights Sheet, 1982-89 (Box 66, Folder 1930)
      - Foreign Rights Sheet, 1978-89 (Box 66, Folder 1931)
      - Invoices, 1974-92, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1932)
      - List of Titles "no royalty paid", n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1933)
      - Marketing Notes, 1987 Mar (Box 66, Folder 1934)
      - Performance Rights Sheet, 1986-87 (Box 66, Folder 1935)
      - Permission to Reprint Copyrighted Material forms, 1974-75 (Box 66, Folder 1936)
      - Quarterly Statements, 1989-90 (Box 66, Folder 1937)
      - Receipts, 1982-91 (Box 66, Folder 1938)
      - Returned Checks, 1976 Oct 13 (Box 66, Folder 1939)
      - Special Meeting of Shareholders Proxy Statement, 1987 Jul 23 (Box 66, Folder 1940)
      - Subsidiary Rights Information Sheet, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1941)
      - Unpublished Trade Contracts, [1974?] (Box 66, Folder 1942)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Manuscript Submissions
      - Notebook for 1961-1962, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1943)
      - Notebook for 1961-1963, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1944)
      - Notebook for 1961-1963, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1945)
    - Translation Project
      - Correspondence and evaluations, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1946)
      - Kurman, George, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1947)
      - Latortue, Régine, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1948)
      - Lewis, Harry, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1949)
      - Lyngstad, Sverre, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1950)
      - MacAfee, Norman, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1951)
      - McLean, Sammy, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1952)
      - Maddock, Mary, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1953)
      - Makki, Adam, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1954)
      - Nienow, Elaine, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1955)
      - Padgett, Ron, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1956)
      - Roberts, Moss, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1957)
      - Rose, Marilyn Gaddis, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1958)
      - Rubin, David, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1959)
      - Schomer, Karine, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1960)
      - Schwartz, Marian, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1961)
      - Tripi, Cecilia Liang, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1962)
      - Vesenyi, Paul E., [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1963)
      - Vo-Dinh, Mai, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1964)
      - Weaver, Kathleen, [1983] (Box 67, Folder 1965)
    - Other Papers
      - Galley proof for unidentified title page verso, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 1966)
      - Material relating to Boris Pasternak, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1967)
      - Material relating to Georges Simenon, 1966-87, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1968)
      - Material relating to Iris Origo, 1979, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1969)
      - Notes and printed selections for anthology of Anne Morrow Lindbergh, [1988?] (Box 68, Folder 1970)
      - Order forms, 1970, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1971)
      - Out of Print titles, 1983 Jul (Box 68, Folder 1972)
      - Publication lists, 1962-83 (Box 68, Folder 1973)
      - Reader reports by Helen Wolff, 1965-93, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1974)
      - Reader reports by others, 1986-89, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1975)
      - Reader reports by unidentified readers, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1976)
      - Translation evaluations, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1977)
- Writings, 1905-1992; Series V; 3.13' (8 boxes)
  Series V, Writings, is organized into three subseries: Writings of Kurt Wolff, Writings of Helen Wolff, and Writings of Others.
  - WRITINGS OF KURT WOLFF
    - Radio Broadcasts
      - "Carl Sternheim"
        - Background material and notes, 1960, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1978)
        - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1979)
      - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 69, Folder 1980)
      - Draft, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 69, Folder 1981)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1982)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1983)
      - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 69, Folder 1984)
      - Draft (incomplete), typescript carbon, corrected, 1961 Dec 7 (Box 69, Folder 1985)
      - "Lesebuch des Dritten Programms. Ausgewählt und Begründet... Carl Sternheim," typescript carbon, 1962 Apr 14 (Box 69, Folder 1986)
      - "Expressionismus I"
        - Background material (Box 69, Folder 1987)
        - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, 1961 Dec 7 (Box 69, Folder 1988)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1989)
        - "Lesebuch des Dritten Programms. Ausgewählt und Begründet... Expressionismus (I)," typescript carbon, 1962 Jan 27 (Box 69, Folder 1990)
      - "Expressionismus II"
        - Background material (Box 69, Folder 1991)
        - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 69, Folder 1992)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [1962 Feb 16?] (Box 69, Folder 1993)
        - "Lesebuch des Dritten Programms. Augewählt und begründet... Expressionismus (II)," typescript carbon, 1962 Feb 16 (Box 69, Folder 1994)
      - "Der Expressionismus und sein Verleger Kurt Wolff als Wegbereiter neuer Dichtung"
        - Interview, typescript, 1975 Jul 12 (Box 69, Folder 1995)
      - "Franz Kafka"
        - Background material and notes (Box 69, Folder 1996)
        - Draft, holograph, typescript and printed fragments, corrected (Box 69, Folder 1997)
        - Draft, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 69, Folder 1998)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [1962 Mar 10?] (Box 69, Folder 1999)
        - "Lesebuch des Dritten Programms. Augewählt und begründet... Franz Kafka," typescript carbon, 1962 Mar 10 (Box 69, Folder 2000)
      - "Franz Werfel"
        - Background material and notes (Box 70, Folder 2001)
        - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2002)
        - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 70, Folder 2003)
        - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 70, Folder 2004)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2005)
        - "Lesebuch des Dritten Programms. Augewählt und begründet... Franz Werfel," typescript, 1962 May 19 (Box 70, Folder 2006)
      - "Karl Kraus"
        - Background material, 1917-62 (Box 70, Folder 2007)
        - Research notes, 1962, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2008)
        - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2009)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2010)
        - "Lesebuch des Dritten Programms. Kurt Wolff und Karl Kraus," typescript carbon, 1963 Jan 2 (Box 70, Folder 2011)
      - "Kurt Wolff erzählt I. Vom Verlegen im Allgemeinen und von der Frage..."
        - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 70, Folder 2012)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, 1964 Mar (Box 70, Folder 2013)
      - "Kurt Wolff erzählt II. Vom Abwerben oder..."
        - Draft, typescript carbon, 1964 Mar 29 (Box 70, Folder 2014)
      - "Kurt Wolff erzählt (III). Abenteuer"
        - Draft, typescript carbon, 1964 May 6 (Box 70, Folder 2015)
      - "Wer war Lou von Salomé?"
        - Background material, 1905-1963, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2016)
        - Research notes, [ca. 1962-63] (Box 70, Folder 2017-2018)
        - Draft, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 71, Folder 2019)
        - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 71, Folder 2020)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2021)
        - Draft (incomplete), typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 71, Folder 2022)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 71, Folder 2023)
        - Draft, typescript photocopy, corrected, 1963 Sep 4 (Box 71, Folder 2024)
    - Other Writings
      - "Begegnung mit dem Absoluten"
        - Article, printed version, Forvm, 1956 Jun (Box 71, Folder 2025)
      - "Bericht über die Jung-Frued Correspondence"
        - Notes, holograph and typescript carbon (Box 71, Folder 2026)
      - "Boris Pasternak..."
        - Background material (Box 71, Folder 2027)
        - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2028)
        - Draft, holograph, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2029)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1962 Oct 9 (Box 71, Folder 2030)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2031)
      - Briefwechsel eines Verlegers 1911-1963
        - Printed version, corrected, 1966 (Box 71, Folder 2032)
        - Publicity, 1966 (Box 71, Folder 2033)
        - Reviews, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2034)
      - Kurt Wolff: A Portrait in Essays & Letters
        - Draft, printout, corrected, [ca. 1991] (Box 72, Folder 2035)
        - Drafts, outline, printout photocopy, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2036)
        - Jacket blurb, 1991 Mar 29 (Box 72, Folder 2037)
        - List of reviewers, 1991 Jun 11 (Box 72, Folder 2038)
      - Letters
        - Page proofs, 1964 Nov 2 (Box 72, Folder 2039)
      - "Lou Andreas-Salomé: Ein Porträt aus Erinnerungen und Dokumenten"
        - Article, printed version, gehört gelesen, 1963 Oct (Box 72, Folder 2040)
      - ["Das Phänomen der Überschneidung..."]
        - Drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 72, Folder 2041)
      - "Plan zur Begründung eines Verlagshauses für Literatur, Geist und Kunst in Darmstadt
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [ca. 1914] (Box 72, Folder 2042)
      - "Porträt der Zeit im Zwiegespräch"
        - Notes, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2043)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2044)
      - "Rabindranath Tagore"
        - Background material, 1962, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2045)
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2046)
        - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2047)
        - Draft, printout, corrected, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2048)
      - "Vom Verlegen im Allgemeinen und von der Frage: wie kommen Verleger und Autoren zusammen"
        - Offprint, Sprache im Technischen Zeitalter, 1964 Nov (Box 72, Folder 2049)
      - "Was man auch übersetzen kann..." essay, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 72, Folder 2050)
      - Untitled "Vortrag"
        - Drafts, holograph, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 72, Folder 2051)
  - WRITINGS OF HELEN WOLFF
    - "Gegenwärtige Erinnerungen an Uwe Johnson," article, typescript photocopy, corrected, 1992 Jul (Box 73, Folder 2052)
    - "Heimito von Doderer," drafts, article, typescript and typescript photocopy, corrected, 1967 Aug 25 (Box 73, Folder 2053)
    - "Heinrich Scheffler, Freund und Verlagspartner"
      - Draft, typescript photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2054)
      - Printed version, Einem Verleger ins Stammbuch, 1980 (Box 73, Folder 2055)
    - ["I first met H.A. in New York..."], article, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2056)
    - ["I have been asked to speak..."], speech, typescript, corrected, [1976] (Box 73, Folder 2057)
    - ["In speaking to you about Uwe Johnson..."], drafts, lecture, holograph and typescript photocopy, corrected, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 2058)
    - "Maigret and the Psycopaths," article, typescript photocopy (Box 73, Folder 2059)
    - "A Publisher Who was Dedicated to Education," letter to the editor, printed version, 1990 May 30 (Box 73, Folder 2060)
    - "Reminiscences," [article?], printout, corrected, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2061)
    - "Translation Then and Now," article, typescript carbon, corrected, 1983 Nov 30 (Box 73, Folder 2062)
    - "Translator and Publisher," article, typescript photocopy, corrected (Box 73, Folder 2063)
    - "Translator Extraordinary and Friend: Richard Winston," article, printed version, Translation Review, 1982 (Box 73, Folder 2064)
    - ["What the publisher needs..."], lecture, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2065)
    - ["When Georges Simenon died..."], [letter to editor?], holograph and printout photocopy, corrected, [1989?] (Box 73, Folder 2066)
    - ["When Mrs. Schloendorff..."], lecture, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1990 (Box 73, Folder 2067)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Altenheim, Hans
      - "Dichters Preis und Lohn," article, offprint, 1987 (Box 74, Folder 2068)
    - Ames, Amyas
      - "The Whippet," poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2069)
    - Arendt, Hannah
      - ["You asked for a statement..."], letter to the editor,' printed version, New York Times Book Review, 1963 Jun 23
    - Arndt, [Walter?]
      - Poems, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2070)
        Translations of poems by Ezrokhi, Lisnyanskaya, and Nikolaevan
    - Arnheim, Rudolf
      - "Arme Irre," printed version, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2071)
    - [Bahr, Hermann?]
      - "Das deutsche Wesen ist uns Erschienen!" [transcription of article?], Kriegssegen, typescript carbon, 1915 (Box 74, Folder 2072)
    - Bihalji-Merin, Oto
      - "Die Plastik der Bogomilen," article, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2073)
    - Blass, Ernst
      - "Georg Heym," article, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, transcription from Aktion, 1912 Jul 12 (Box 74, Folder 2074)
    - Broch, Hermann
      - "Hermann Broch/Daniel Brody: Briefwechsel 1930-1951," correspondence, printed version, Börsenblatt für den Deutschen Buchhandel, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 2075)
    - Brown, Calvin S. [(Calvin Smith)?]
      - "Translating Rilke's French and German Poems," article, printed version, Sewanee Review, photocopy, 1986 (Box 74, Folder 2076)
    - Busch, Adolf
      - [ Letters, Pictures, Memories ?], draft, typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2077-2078)
    - Calvino, Italo
      - ["For the writer of a language..."], autobiographical statement, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2079)
    - Cane, Melville
      - Poems, 1961-69, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2080)
    - Cibulka, Hans
      Poems, printout photocopy